{
    "id": "19f4152dd624400aa655941717944c3a",
    "title": "Linking Expressions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I think we will win the match. We have got the best players. ...................................., our coach is fantastic.",
            "description": "Moreover is used to introduce an additional and important fact that supports what you have just said.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "All the same",
                "Nevertheless",
                "Moreover"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "71c42fddde4f4c83a3c68ec5670b8e8d"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was hired .......................................... the fact that he had very little experience.",
            "description": "We need a preposition before the phrase ‘the fact that’. Despite is a preposition. Despite is used for saying that something happens even though something else might have prevented it. Despite can be directly followed by a noun. Example: He was hired despite his lack of experience. Despite cannot be directly followed by a that-clause. Therefore we use the phrase ‘despite the fact that’.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "even though",
                "despite",
                "even if"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6f0770aac45248d6b0acf7298d968b02"
        },
        {
            "question": "Many people are successful in their careers ......................... the fact that they do not have a university degree.",
            "description": "In spite of is a preposition. Since prepositions cannot be directly followed by that-clauses, they take the phrase ‘the fact’.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "although",
                "even though",
                "in spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c22b96d87fa447b196a01b4095cfa0c3"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. theoretical knowledge can be acquired from books, skills must be gained through practice.",
            "description": "Whereas is used to compare two people or things and to show that there is an important difference between them.",
            "answers": [
                "Even as",
                "Even so",
                "Whereas"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4676fbcf97b249b9b62feee02f5a440f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Train accidents are rare, but, ......................................, there should be stricter safety regulations.",
            "description": "Even so is used to introduce a statement that might seem surprising in the light of what you said before.",
            "answers": [
                "even as",
                "even if",
                "even so",
                "even though"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1ff8000ca7384807bef639da489f480a"
        },
        {
            "question": "He lost the game but he has improved a lot ..................................",
            "description": "Nonetheless can go at the end of a sentence. This sentence can also be written as:He lost the game nonetheless, he has improved a lot.",
            "answers": [
                "despite",
                "whereas",
                "nonetheless"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "bdb5d0d98baf43e0aa365438ab98c206"
        },
        {
            "question": "The rehabilitation program has saved thousands of children who would ...................................... have died in the famine.",
            "description": "Otherwise is used to suggest that if one thing does not happen, something else (usually something bad) will happen.",
            "answers": [
                "instead",
                "unless",
                "otherwise",
                "despite"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4ff9222d106d4b468b6cdd9e3be893e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "She didn’t allow the setbacks to discourage her. ........................................, she began to work twice as hard.",
            "description": "On the contrary is used to strengthen a negative statement the writer or speaker has just made.",
            "answers": [
                "On the other hand",
                "On the contrary",
                "In fact",
                "Nevertheless"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5b7f9bf7ff5849a3aba600d63f5cd0ec"
        },
        {
            "question": "Exposure to sunlight will spoil wine ...................................... wine bottles are made of yellow or green glass.",
            "description": "Hence is used for introducing the result / effect of the fact that has just been mentioned.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "then",
                "hence",
                "in most cases"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1aaec45948b34b0599c70b5956fd98e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The house was quiet ........................................ the noise of Mary typing.",
            "description": "'Except' and 'except for' are used to introduce exceptions to generalizations. Except is not possible here. It can be used without 'for' only after generalizing words like all, every, no, everything, anybody, nowhere, whole etc.",
            "answers": [
                "except",
                "except for",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d55b9776d70c48a79f13d686d0873104"
        },
        {
            "question": "......................................... we have already discussed the dangers of smoking, I think the information bears being repeated.",
            "description": "Although is used for introducing a statement that makes your main statement seem surprising.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "Despite",
                "Even as",
                "As"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1a35adc5edba44c782e33c3f506ab650"
        },
        {
            "question": "I hardly knew anybody at the party ..................................... Peter and William.",
            "description": "After negative expressions like no, nobody, nothing and hardly, all three of these words can be used with the same meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "except",
                "besides",
                "apart from",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "6249c9b5f5cd47ca94c19b8f2f3d91ee"
        }
    ]
}